Roslyn Brogue Henning Papers MS077
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Roslyn Brogue Henning Papers
1950 -- 1960
1919 -- 1996
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Henning, Roslyn Brogue
MS077
144.57 Linear Feet 12 oversize boxes, 1 letter size document box, 1 record carton
Arrangement
This collection is organized in one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains original compositions by Tufts faculty member Roslyn Brogue Henning, scrapbooks from 1919 to 1965, containing concert programs, diary entries, clippings and photographs, as well as a file of personal and Tufts related correspondence. The collection consists of sheet music, some printed and some handwritten in a box called "Manuscripts."
Biographical / Historical
Roslyn Brogue Henning (1919-1981) was a Tufts professor, composer, musician and classics scholar. Henning studied at Drake University and at the University of Chicago, where she received a degree in classics at the age of 19. She continued her education at Radcliffe College earning a M.A. in 1943 and a PhD. from Harvard University in 1947. She married composer Ervin Henning in 1944. She joined the Tufts Department of Classics in 1962 as an associate professor. Henning was also a member of the American Music Center in New York and AFL-CIO Local #9. She played a number of instruments including the harpsichord, piano, and violin and went on to join the Department of Music at Tufts. Henning was well-known locally as a composer, with 26 works to her credit. Her compositions were performed in Boston and New York. In 1965, she was the recipient of the Brookline Library Music Association's composition prize for her String Quartet. Her teaching career at Tufts spanned 13 years, ending with her retirement in 1975.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Henning, Roslyn Brogue; Faculty papers; Music
- Roslyn Brogue Henning, papers, 1919 -- 1996; 1950 -- 1960; MS077.001; 10.8 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains original compositions by Tufts faculty member Roslyn Brogue Henning. The collection consists of sheet music, some printed and some handwritten in a box called "Manuscripts," and Henning's scrapbooks from 1919 to 1965, containing concert programs, diary entries, clippings and photographs.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by scores and then alphabetically by subject.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Adoramus Te, MS077.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Allegretto for Flute and Piano, MS077.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Andante and Variations for Harpsichord and Orchestra, MS077.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Arabesque for Cello and Piano, MS077.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - The Baite, MS077.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Come, Lovely and Soothing Death, MS077.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Chambermusic, No. 2, 1942; MS077.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
    Inscribed: To Marguerite Pettes Chambermusic, No. 2, December, 1942 Fragment from a Trio-Sonato Roslyn Brogue
    score
  - Darest Thou Now O Soul, MS077.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Duo Lirico for Violin and Harpsichord, MS077.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Equipoise I and II, MS077.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Four Elegies, MS077.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - The Juggler, MS077.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Passage to India, MS077.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Quartet for Strings, MS077.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Quintet for Winds, parts and score, MS077.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Quodlibet for Flute, Cello, and Harpsichord, MS077.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Sonatina for Flute, Clarinet, and Harpsichord, MS077.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Sonnet from the Portuguese, MS077.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Praxagora, 1942; MS077.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Speed, We Say, MS077.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Suite for Recorders Parade, MS077.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - The Sunne Rising, MS077.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Symphonia Missae for Organ, MS077.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Trio for Oboe, Clarinet, and Bassoon, MS077.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Trio for Violin, Clarinet, and Piano, MS077.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - When Our Two Souls..., MS077.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Woodwind Quintet with Organ, MS077.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - A Valediction of Weeping, MS077.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Childing, MS077.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Love Songs After the Provencal and other scores, MS077.001.007 (Box 7)
  - The Baite; and Speed, We Say, 1961; MS077.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Childing; and Sonatina for Flute, Clarinet, and Harpsichord, 1957; MS077.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Come, Lovely and Soothing Death, 1960; MS077.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - Five Songs, 1958; MS077.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Passage to India, MS077.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Song of Exploration, 1960; MS077.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - Valediction of Weeping; The Juggler; Four Elegies, 1962; MS077.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Darest Thou Now; Passage to India; Ode; Recitative and Epode, 1962; MS077.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - Quartet for Piano and Strings -- Mille Regretz and other manuscripts, 1950 -- 1960; MS077.001.009 (Box 9)
  - Song of Exploration, 1950 -- 1960; MS077.001.010.00001 (Box 10)
  - Suite for Orchestra, 1950 -- 1960; MS077.001.011.00001 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1947 -- 1961; MS077.001.012.00001 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook, 1961 -- 1965; MS077.001.012.00002 (Box 12)
  - Roslyn Brogue vertical file, 1963 -- 1996; MS077.001.012.00003 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook, 1919 -- 1935; MS077.001.013.00001 (Box Shared 139)
  - Transparencies and copies of scores, 1947 -- 1965; MS077.001.014 (Box data_value_missing_db14d918660192b2b7f7c58bb013dc09, Box 14)
    former barcode 39090014024984g